<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Choria Orchestrator</title>
    <link>http://docs.choria.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Choria Orchestrator</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://docs.choria.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Choria</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Choria is a distribution of plugins and utilities that enhances &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.puppet.com/mcollective/&#34;&gt;The Marionette Collective&lt;/a&gt; from Puppet Inc with modern abilities and significantly improves the getting started experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MCollective is notoriously hard to install, the official installation guide takes you through pages and pages of information and expect you to make very important decisions that affects the security of your platform before you even know the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choria exists to provide a distribution of plugins designed to be secure by default, easy to install and with no prior knowledge required to get to a point of having a secure production ready deployment of MCollective. Even a clustered setup of MCollective using Choria should take less than 1 hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After installing MCollective using Choria you can be sure that the security decisions taken are robust and the full Authentication, Authorization and Auditing feature set that sets MCollective apart from others have been configured for you.  Choria was written by the original architect of The Marionette Collective and represents current thinking on deployment and security of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Security Plugin utilizing the Puppet 4 Certificate Authority system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Discovery plugin for PuppetDB giving you a responsive and predictable interaction mode with support for PQL based infrastructure discovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Orchestrator for the Puppet Multi Node Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Connector using NATS.io middleware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full end to end Authentication, Authorization and Auditing out of the box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common Puppet eco system plugins like Package, Service, Puppet and File Manager deployed and ready to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating System support for every OS Puppet 4 AIO supports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for SRV records and sane configuration defaults to attain a zero config setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;../deployment&#34;&gt;Deployment Guide&lt;/a&gt; for details on installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;status&#34;&gt;Status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the features of this module work as intended, though bugs are inevitable.  All AIO supported Operating Systems are supported, including Windows, and the project is under active development on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ripienaar/mcollective-choria&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deployment</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;deployment&#34;&gt;Deployment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choria is designed to install MCollective very easily, the installation is completely driven by Puppet and Hiera and have very few requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After following this guide you will have a fully functional MCollective set up with TLS encryption, full Authentication, Authorization and Auditing and several useful plugins configured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you have to do things like open up Firewall ports it&amp;rsquo;s anticipated that deploying MCollective using Choria should not take longer than 1 hour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/requirements/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For MCollective to function we need a few infrastructure components, this guide takes you through setting up all of these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up a middleware broker using &lt;a href=&#34;https://nats.io/&#34;&gt;NATS.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure server locations using DNS or manually if not using defaults&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure MCollective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create your first user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are very few requirements, a typical up to date Puppet installation following official guidelines will do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;required&#34;&gt;Required&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must use Puppet 4 deployed using the Puppet Inc AIO packages - the one called &lt;em&gt;puppet-agent&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must be using a Puppet Master based setup, typically using &lt;em&gt;puppetserver&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your mcollective &lt;em&gt;server.cfg&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;client.cfg&lt;/em&gt; should be Factory Default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your SSL certificates should be in the default locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to run middleware, Choria works best with NATS and provides a module to install that for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your certnames must match your FQDNs - the default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forge.puppet.com/ripienaar/mcollective&#34;&gt;ripienaar-mcollective&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://forge.puppet.com/ripienaar/nats&#34;&gt;ripienaar-nats&lt;/a&gt; modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;optional&#34;&gt;Optional&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An optional PuppetDB integration exist to use PuppetDB as the source of truth.  This requires PuppetDB and extra configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Puppet Applications are supported and deployment can be done using Choria, it requires specific setup of your &lt;em&gt;puppetserver&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NATS Middleware</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/nats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/nats/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Choria uses the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://nats.io/&#34;&gt;NATS.io&lt;/a&gt; broker by default.  It&amp;rsquo;s very fast, light weight, has a simple configuration and is easy to monitor.  It&amp;rsquo;s configured to only accept connections from nodes with certificates signed by the Puppet CA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One NATS server has been shown to be able to host over 2000 MCollective nodes comfortably using 300MB RAM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broker nodes must be managed by Puppet and have certs signed by your CA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brokers must run on systemd capable hosts such as CentOS 7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to get the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forge.puppet.com/ripienaar/nats&#34;&gt;ripienaar-nats&lt;/a&gt; module from the Puppet Forge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to ensure that port &lt;code&gt;4222&lt;/code&gt; is reachable from all your Puppet nodes on all NATS servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to ensure that in a clustered environment port &lt;code&gt;4223&lt;/code&gt; is reachable by the NATS cluster hosts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you wish to use the &lt;em&gt;collectd&lt;/em&gt; integration, port &lt;code&gt;8222&lt;/code&gt; must be reachable from &lt;em&gt;localhost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;single-or-multiple-nodes&#34;&gt;Single or multiple nodes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision to run multiple nodes is about availability and scale.  As mentioned NATS can easily handle large numbers of nodes on a single broker, if this is your first deployment there is no reason right now to think about a cluster of brokers.  As you&amp;rsquo;ll see configuring a cluster is very easy and easily done later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose to do 1 only keep it simple and install it on your Puppet Master.  This removes the need to configure DNS (the next section) and gets you going ready to explore the possibilities quickly, you can easily later add servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;single-node&#34;&gt;Single node&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you just want to run a single NATS server I suggest putting this on the same machine as your Puppet Server which would by default be resolvable as &lt;em&gt;puppet&lt;/em&gt;.  This means you do not need to configure anything in Choria as that&amp;rsquo;s the default it assumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-puppet&#34;&gt;node &amp;quot;puppet.example.net&amp;quot; {
  class{&amp;quot;nats: }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cluster-of-nats-brokers&#34;&gt;Cluster of NATS Brokers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can create a cluster of brokers, pick 3 or 5 machines and include the module on them all listing the entire cluster certnames. If you do a cluster you must configure Choria via &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.choria.io/deployment/nats/&#34;&gt;DNS or manually&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-puppet&#34;&gt;node &amp;quot;nats1.example.net&amp;quot; {
  class{&amp;quot;nats:
    routes_password =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Vrph54FBcIvdM&amp;quot;
    servers =&amp;gt; [
      &amp;quot;nats1.example.net&amp;quot;,
      &amp;quot;nats2.example.net&amp;quot;,
      &amp;quot;nats3.example.net&amp;quot;,
      &amp;quot;nats4.example.net&amp;quot;,
      &amp;quot;nats5.example.net&amp;quot;
    ],
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;collectd-integration&#34;&gt;Collectd Integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use the &lt;em&gt;puppet-collectd&lt;/em&gt; module you can optionally integrate with that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-puppet&#34;&gt;node &amp;quot;puppet.example.net&amp;quot; {
  class{&amp;quot;nats:
    manage_collectd =&amp;gt; true
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS Setup</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/dns/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;By default as per Puppet behaviour the Puppet Master, Puppet CA and NATS brokers are all found on the name &lt;em&gt;puppet&lt;/em&gt;.  If you are doing a single node NATS installation on the Puppet Master called &lt;em&gt;puppet&lt;/em&gt; you do not neeed to configure anything and continue to the next page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When not using &lt;em&gt;puppet&lt;/em&gt; you can configure these settings manually but we strongly suggest you use SRV records if at all possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nats-brokers&#34;&gt;NATS Brokers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can configure where your NATS brokers live using these SRV records:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;_x-puppet-mcollective._tcp   IN  SRV 10  0 4222  nats1.example.net.
_x-puppet-mcollective._tcp   IN  SRV 11  0 4222  nats2.example.net.
_x-puppet-mcollective._tcp   IN  SRV 12  0 4222  nats3.example.net.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means you have 3 of them and they all listen on port &lt;em&gt;4222&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;puppet-and-puppet-ca&#34;&gt;Puppet and Puppet CA&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your Puppet CA, PuppetDB and Puppet Server are all on the same host, you can configure that all with a single SRV record that is compatible with Puppet SRV setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;_x-puppet._tcp               IN  SRV 10  0 8140  puppet1.example.net.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you wish to split the CA and DB from the master add these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;_x-puppet-ca._tcp            IN  SRV 10  0 8140  puppetca1.example.net.
_x-puppet-db._tcp            IN  SRV 10  0 8081  puppetdb1.example.net.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-domain&#34;&gt;Custom Domain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default these SRV records will be looked for in your machines &lt;em&gt;domain&lt;/em&gt; fact, but you can customize this by creating data in your &lt;em&gt;Hiera&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective_choria::config:
  srv_domain: &amp;quot;prod.example.net&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;manual-config&#34;&gt;Manual Config&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have to you can configure these locations manually by creating &lt;em&gt;Hiera&lt;/em&gt; data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective_choria::config:
  puppetserver_host: &amp;quot;puppet1.example.net&amp;quot;
  puppetserver_port: 8140
  puppetca_host: &amp;quot;ca1.example.net&amp;quot;
  puppetca_port: 8140
  puppetdb_host: &amp;quot;pdb1.example.net&amp;quot;
  puppetdb_port: 8081
  middleware_hosts:
    - &amp;quot;nats1.example.net:4222&amp;quot;
    - &amp;quot;nats2.example.net:4222&amp;quot;
    - &amp;quot;nats3.example.net:4222&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCollective</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/mcollective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/mcollective/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Configuring MCollective with Choria is generally very simple and involves just including 1 module and setting some Hiera data, it takes care of the entire process for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In MCollective terminology a &lt;em&gt;client&lt;/em&gt; is one you manage your network from - where you run &lt;em&gt;mco&lt;/em&gt; commands - and a &lt;em&gt;server&lt;/em&gt; is a node being managed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-node&#34;&gt;Every node&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All nodes should have the &lt;em&gt;ripienaar-mcollective&lt;/em&gt; module on them, by default every node becomes a MCollective Server ready to be managed via MCollective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-puppet&#34;&gt;node &amp;quot;server1.example.net&amp;quot; {
  include mcollective
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;client-nodes&#34;&gt;Client nodes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On machines where you wish to run &lt;em&gt;mco&lt;/em&gt; commands like your Bastion nodes you have to configure them to be clients, you do this via &lt;em&gt;Hiera&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective::client: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to have Client Only machines, you can disable the server on them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective::client: true
mcollective::server: false
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First User</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/first-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/first-user/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Users who wish to manage nodes via MCollective need to have certificates signed by the Puppet CA.  Choria includes a tool to request and manage these certificates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-your-first-user&#34;&gt;Create your first user&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the node you wish to run MCollective commands from you should have configured it as a &lt;em&gt;client&lt;/em&gt; in the previous step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ whoami
rip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are ready request the certificate from the CA, it will store it in the default location in &lt;em&gt;~/.puppetlabs&lt;/em&gt; as per Puppet AIO standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices warning&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;You should not run any &lt;em&gt;mco&lt;/em&gt; commands as &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt;, this will produce an error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco choria request_cert
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will request a certificate from your Puppet CA, you should sign it there and once signed it will be downloaded and saved.  If you cannot sign it immediately you can safely run this command again later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default as my username is &lt;em&gt;rip&lt;/em&gt; the certificate that was requested will be &lt;em&gt;rip.mcollective&lt;/em&gt;.  The default Choria setup only allows &lt;em&gt;*.mcollective&lt;/em&gt; as certificate names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should now be able to run &lt;em&gt;mco ping&lt;/em&gt; and see some of your nodes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco ping
dev1.example.net                           time=55.35 ms
dev2.example.net                           time=57.67 ms
dev3.example.net                           time=59.52 ms
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most other commands will not work due to the &lt;em&gt;default deny&lt;/em&gt; nature of the Choria so you have to set up some Authorization rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;authorization&#34;&gt;Authorization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my user certificate is &lt;em&gt;rip.mcollective&lt;/em&gt; and I wish to be able to manage all aspects of my MCollective I am going to add a default allow rule to &lt;em&gt;Hiera&lt;/em&gt;, add this to your common tier or whichever tier will select the nodes you wish to be able to manage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective::site_policies:
  - action: &amp;quot;allow&amp;quot;
    callers: &amp;quot;choria=rip.mcollective&amp;quot;
    actions: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
    facts: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
    classes: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this has been rolled out to your site you can go ahead and try commands like &lt;code&gt;mco puppet status&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to deploy further users I suggest you look at the &lt;a href=&#34;../../configuration/aaa/&#34;&gt;MCollective AAA&lt;/a&gt; documentation section.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Steps</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/next-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/deployment/next-steps/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At this point you should have a working MCollective set up with your user able to do any command of the plugins we deployed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;confirming-it-is-working&#34;&gt;Confirming it is working&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the shell you set up the user in lets check the version of &lt;em&gt;puppet-agent&lt;/em&gt; installed on your nodes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco package status puppet-agent

 * [ ============================================================&amp;gt; ] 15 / 15

                 dev1.example.net: puppet-agent-1.8.0-1.el7.x86_64
                 dev2.example.net: puppet-agent-1.8.0-1.el7.x86_64
                 dev3.example.net: puppet-agent-1.8.0-1.el7.x86_64

Summary of Arch:

   x86_64 = 3

Summary of Ensure:

   1.8.0-1.el7 = 3


Finished processing 3 / 3 hosts in 71.63 ms
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MCollective knows a lot about your nodes such as all their Facts and Puppet Classes deployed to them, you
can view what it knows about a certain node, this should include your classes, facts and agents deployed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices tip&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;MCollective identities match the certificate names from Puppet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco inventory dev1.example.net

Inventory for dev1.example.net:

   Server Statistics:
                      Version: 2.9.1
                   Start Time: 2016-12-16 21:35:20 +0100
                  Config File: /etc/puppetlabs/mcollective/server.cfg
                  Collectives: de_collective, mcollective
              Main Collective: mcollective
                   Process ID: 13127
               Total Messages: 12
      Messages Passed Filters: 12
            Messages Filtered: 0
             Expired Messages: 0
                 Replies Sent: 11
         Total Processor Time: 35.85 seconds
                  System Time: 16.33 seconds

   Agents:
      discovery       filemgr         package
      puppet          rpcutil         service

   Data Plugins:
      agent           collective      fact
      fstat           puppet          resource
      service

   Configuration Management Classes:
    mcollective                           mcollective::config
    mcollective::facts                    mcollective::packager
    mcollective::plugin_dirs              mcollective::service
    mcollective_agent_filemgr             mcollective_agent_iptables
    mcollective_agent_package             mcollective_agent_puppet
    mcollective_agent_puppetca            mcollective_agent_service
    mcollective_choria                    mcollective_util_actionpolicy

   Facts:
      aio_agent_version =&amp;gt; 1.8.0
      architecture =&amp;gt; x86_64
      augeas =&amp;gt; {&amp;quot;version&amp;quot;=&amp;gt;&amp;quot;1.4.0&amp;quot;}
      augeasversion =&amp;gt; 1.4.0
      ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get a quick report of values for some fact (add -v for node names):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;Report for fact: aio_agent_version

        1.8.0                                    found 3 times

Finished processing 3 / 3 hosts in 18.61 ms
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can check that the Puppet service is up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco service status puppet

 * [ ============================================================&amp;gt; ] 3 / 3

   dev3.example.net: running
   dev2.example.net: running
   dev1.example.net: running

Summary of Service Status:

   running = 3


Finished processing 3 / 3 hosts in 98.98 ms
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when last Puppet ran on these nodes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco puppet status

 * [ ============================================================&amp;gt; ] 3 / 3

   dev1.example.net: Currently idling; last completed run 6 minutes 20 seconds ago
   dev2.example.net: Currently idling; last completed run 10 minutes 04 seconds ago
   dev3.example.net: Currently idling; last completed run 25 seconds ago

Summary of Applying:

   false = 3

Summary of Daemon Running:

   running = 3

Summary of Enabled:

   enabled = 3

Summary of Idling:

   true = 3

Summary of Status:

   idling = 3


Finished processing 3 / 3 hosts in 28.27 ms
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is much to learn about MCollective, at this point if all worked you&amp;rsquo;ll have a setup
that is secured by using TLS on every middleware connection and every user securely identified
and authorized via the Puppet SSL certificates with auditing and logging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choria has a few optional features related to integration with PuppetDB and Puppet Server,
please see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://choria.io/configuration/&#34;&gt;optional configuration&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official documentation is a good resource for usage details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I strongly suggest you read about &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.puppet.com/mcollective/reference/basic/basic_cli_usage.html&#34;&gt;using the mcollective CLI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read about &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.puppet.com/mcollective/reference/ui/filters.html&#34;&gt;filtering which hosts to act on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/puppetlabs/mcollective-puppet-agent#usage&#34;&gt;managing Puppet&lt;/a&gt; though note the setup steps are already completed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/puppetlabs/mcollective-package-agent#readme&#34;&gt;managing packages&lt;/a&gt; though note the setup steps are already completed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/puppetlabs/mcollective-service-agent#readme&#34;&gt;managing services&lt;/a&gt; though note the setup steps are already completed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/puppetlabs/mcollective-filemgr-agent#readme&#34;&gt;managing files&lt;/a&gt; and this setup too is already completed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These plugins that manage Service, Package, Puppet and Files are just plugins and they make the
core feature set of Mcollective.  You can write your own plugins, deploy them and interact with
them.  There is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.puppet.com/mcollective/simplerpc/agents.html&#34;&gt;official guide about this&lt;/a&gt;.
Writing your own lets you solve your deployment problems using MCollective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-in-touch&#34;&gt;Getting in touch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am on the Puppet IRC as &lt;em&gt;Volcane&lt;/em&gt; and on slack as &lt;em&gt;ripienaar&lt;/em&gt;, we also have a &lt;em&gt;#mcollective&lt;/em&gt; channel on Freenode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to file a ticket about anything here or improve something the 2 GitHub project are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ripienaar/mcollective-choria&#34;&gt;ripienaar/mcollective-choria&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ripienaar/puppet-mcollective&#34;&gt;ripienaar/puppet-mcollective&lt;/a&gt; where you can file issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optional Configuration</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;optional-configuration&#34;&gt;Optional Configuration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past the initial &lt;a href=&#34;../deployment&#34;&gt;Deployment&lt;/a&gt; there are a few extra, but optional, things you can configure using Choria which this section covers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PuppetDB Discovery</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/puppetdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/puppetdb/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Choria includes a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.puppet.com/puppetdb/&#34;&gt;PuppetDB&lt;/a&gt; based discovery plugin but it&amp;rsquo;s not enabled by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an advanced PuppetDB plugin that is subcollective aware and supports node, fact, class and agent filters. It uses the new &lt;em&gt;Puppet PQL&lt;/em&gt; under the hood and so requires a very recent PuppetDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using it you get a very fast discovery workflow but without the awareness of which nodes are actually up and responding, it&amp;rsquo;s suitable for situations where you have a stable network, or really care to know when known machines are not responding as is common during software deployments. It makes a very comfortable to use default discovery plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your MCollective &lt;em&gt;client&lt;/em&gt; machine needs to be able to communicate with PuppetDB on its SSL port. The client will use the same certificates that was created using _mco choria request&lt;em&gt;cert&lt;/em&gt; so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything with the normal Puppet client-tools config, though you might find setting those up helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices warning&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Giving people access to PuppetDB in this manner will allow them to do all kinds of thing with your data as there are no ACL features in PuppetDB, consider carefully who you allow to connect to PuppetDB on any port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;using&#34;&gt;Using&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general you can just go about using MCollective as normal after configuring it (see below).  All your usual filters like &lt;em&gt;-I&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;-C&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;-W&lt;/em&gt; etc all work as normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your discovery should take a fraction of a second rather than the usual 2 seconds or more and will reflect what PuppetDB thinks it should be out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pql&#34;&gt;PQL&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an advanced feature that lets you construct complex queries using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.puppet.com/puppetdb/latest/api/query/v4/pql.html&#34;&gt;PQL language&lt;/a&gt; for discovery though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco find -I &amp;quot;pql:nodes[certname] { certname ~ &#39;^dev&#39; }&amp;quot;
dev3.example.net
dev1.example.net
dev2.example.net
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can construct very complex queries that can match even to the level of specific properties of resources and classes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco find -I &amp;quot;pql:inventory[certname] { resources { type = &#39;User&#39; and title = &#39;rip&#39; and parameters.ensure = &#39;present&#39;}}&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PQL queries comes in all forms, there are many examples at the Puppet docs. Though you should note that you must ensure you only ever return the certname as in the above example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you configure the Puppet Client Tools (see below) you can test these queries on the CLI:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;% puppet query &amp;quot;inventory[certname] { resources { type = &#39;User&#39; and title = &#39;rip&#39; and parameters.ensure = &#39;present&#39;}}&amp;quot;
[
  {
    &amp;quot;certname&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;host1.example.net&amp;quot;
  }
]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your queries &lt;strong&gt;MUST&lt;/strong&gt; return the data as above - just the certname property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuring-mcollective&#34;&gt;Configuring MCollective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do not have to configure this to be the default discovery method, instead you can use it just when you need or want:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco puppet status --dm=choria
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By passing &lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;dm=choria&lt;/em&gt; to MCollective commands you enable this discovery method just for the duration of that command.  This is a good way to test the feature before enabling it by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can set this discovery method to be your default by adding the following hiera data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective::client_config:
  default_discovery_method: &amp;quot;choria&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default it will attempt to find PuppetDB on puppet:8081, you can configure this &lt;a href=&#34;../../deployment/dns/&#34;&gt;using DNS or manually&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuring-puppet-optional&#34;&gt;Configuring Puppet (optional)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s convenient to be able to query PuppetDB using the &lt;em&gt;puppet query&lt;/em&gt; command especially if you want to use the custom PQL based discovery, create ~/.puppetlabs/client-tools/puppetdb.conf with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;{
  &amp;quot;puppetdb&amp;quot;: {
    &amp;quot;server_urls&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;https://puppet:8081&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;cacert&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/home/rip/.puppetlabs/etc/puppet/ssl/certs/ca.pem&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;cert&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/home/rip/.puppetlabs/etc/puppet/ssl/certs/rip.mcollective.pem&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/home/rip/.puppetlabs/etc/puppet/ssl/private_keys/rip.mcollective.pem&amp;quot;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then install the puppet-client-tools package from the Puppet Labs repos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCollective AAA</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/aaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/aaa/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;MCollective features a full suite of Authentication, Authorization and Auditing capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication - &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; you are, derived from a certificate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorization - &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you may do on any given node, keyed to your certificate based identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auditing - &lt;em&gt;log&lt;/em&gt; of what you did, showing your certificate based identitty and all requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier we made a certificate called &lt;em&gt;rip.mcollective&lt;/em&gt; which is used to establish your identity as &lt;em&gt;choria=rip.mcollective&lt;/em&gt; which will be used throughout in the AAA system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;authorization&#34;&gt;Authorization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choria sets up the popular &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/puppetlabs/mcollective-actionpolicy-auth&#34;&gt;Action Policy&lt;/a&gt; based authorization and does so in a &lt;em&gt;default deny&lt;/em&gt; mode which means by default, no-one can make any requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some plugins may elect to ship authorization rules that allow certain read only actions by default - like the &lt;em&gt;mco puppet status&lt;/em&gt; command, but you can change or override all of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;site-policies&#34;&gt;Site Policies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can allow your own users only certain access, previously when configuring your first user we did this already via &lt;em&gt;Hiera&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective::site_policies:
  - action: &amp;quot;allow&amp;quot;
    callers: &amp;quot;choria=rip.mcollective&amp;quot;
    actions: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
    facts: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
    classes: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll note this is an array so you can have many policies, site policies are applied to &lt;strong&gt;all agents&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;agent-specific-policies&#34;&gt;Agent specific policies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will allow a specific certificate to only &lt;em&gt;block&lt;/em&gt; ip addresses on my firewall but nothing else:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective_agent_iptables::policies:
  - action: &amp;quot;allow&amp;quot;
    callers: &amp;quot;choria=typhon.mcollective&amp;quot;
    actions: &amp;quot;block&amp;quot;
    facts: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
    classes: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For full details see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/puppetlabs/mcollective-actionpolicy-auth&#34;&gt;Action Policy&lt;/a&gt; docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;per-plugin-default-override&#34;&gt;Per plugin default override&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned by default all actions are denied across all agents, you can change a specific agent to default allow via hiera:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective_agent_puppet::policy_default: allow
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;site-wide-default-policy&#34;&gt;Site wide default policy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default all actions are denied, if like in a Lab environment you want to simplify things and all all actions across all agents, you can set this in &lt;em&gt;Hiera&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices warning&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Enabling this will allow anyone with a signed mcollective cert to perform any action on any node, please consider carefully before changing this setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective::policy_default: allow
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;authentication&#34;&gt;Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;custom-certificate-names&#34;&gt;Custom certificate names&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authentication is done via the certname embedded in the certificate, certificates must be signed by the Puppet CA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default the only certificates that will be accepted are those matching the pattern &lt;em&gt;/.mcollective$/&lt;/em&gt;, if you have some special needs you can adjust this via &lt;em&gt;Hiera&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective_choria::config:
  security.certname_whitelist: &amp;quot;bob, jill, /\.mcollective$/&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you can request custom certificate names on the CLI:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco choria request_cert --certname bob
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;revoking-access&#34;&gt;Revoking access&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public certificates are distributed automatically but will never be removed.  To remove them you have to manually arrange for the files to be deleted from all nodes - perhaps using Puppet - before a new one can be distributed.  These live in &lt;em&gt;/etc/puppetlabs/mcollective/choria_security/public_certs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;privileged-certificates&#34;&gt;Privileged certificates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless specifically requested you should never use certificates matching the pattern &lt;em&gt;/.privileged.mcollective$/&lt;/em&gt;, this is an advanced feature that is reserved for a future REST server where Authentication is delegated to a trusted piece of software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;auditing&#34;&gt;Auditing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auditing is configured to write to a log file &lt;em&gt;/var/log/puppetlabs/mcollective-audit.log&lt;/em&gt; by default, you should set up rotation if desired (not done by the module), it&amp;rsquo;s contents are like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;[2016-12-13 08:32:34 UTC] reqid=30d706be63e555db8c073ec17a23af44: reqtime=1481617954 caller=choria=rip.mcollective@dev3.example.net agent=rpcutil action=ping data={:process_results=&amp;gt;true}
[2016-12-13 08:32:43 UTC] reqid=e0c60ad2f58d52699e6524039decc257: reqtime=1481617963 caller=choria=rip.mcollective@dev3.example.net agent=puppet action=status data={:process_results=&amp;gt;true}
[2016-12-13 13:15:09 UTC] reqid=1235e001c9b15414b748ab26607e1063: reqtime=1481634909 caller=choria=rip.mcollective@dev3.example.net agent=puppet action=status data={:process_results=&amp;gt;true}
[2016-12-13 13:15:35 UTC] reqid=cf95bc7621ff55a8a197e3f2e394406e: reqtime=1481634935 caller=choria=rip.mcollective@dev3.example.net agent=puppet action=status data={:process_results=&amp;gt;true}
[2016-12-13 13:15:43 UTC] reqid=18192c7f260c5788a33b60ce4f01771c: reqtime=1481634943 caller=choria=rip.mcollective@dev3.example.net agent=puppet action=status data={:process_results=&amp;gt;true}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Distribution</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/plugins/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;MCollective have many plugins, the most common ones are &lt;em&gt;agents&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past packaging was done via RPM or Deb packages, this was extremely limited requiring extra work to make configuration modules and of course only worked on those operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;packaging&#34;&gt;Packaging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choria includes a packager that turns a common MCollective plugin into a Puppet Module like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forge.puppet.com/ripienaar/mcollective_agent_puppet&#34;&gt;Puppet Agent one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can package your own modules in this manner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ cd youragent
$ mco plugin package --format aiomodulepackage --vendor yourco
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will produce a Puppet module that you can install using Choria by adding it to the list of plugins to manage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective::plugin_classes:
  - mcollective_agent_youragent
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plugin-configuration&#34;&gt;Plugin Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many MCollective plugins have extensive configuration, some times Server and Client side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;ripienaar-mcollective&lt;/em&gt; module lets you configure any setting in any plugin via &lt;em&gt;Hiera&lt;/em&gt; data, here&amp;rsquo;s an example of configuring the Puppet one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective_agent_puppet::config:
  &amp;quot;splay&amp;quot;: false
  &amp;quot;signal_daemon&amp;quot;: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This creates files in &lt;em&gt;/etc/puppetlabs/mcollective/plugin.d&lt;/em&gt; with the per plugin settings.  This will only work on plugins distributed using the method shown above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gem Distribution</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/gems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/gems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many sites have policies prohibiting their nodes from accessing dependencies via the internet.  Choria allows those to manage their own dependencies and disable the built in Gem management:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can package the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rubygems.org/gems/nats-pure&#34;&gt;nats-pure&lt;/a&gt; dependency yourself, perhaps using &lt;a href=&#34;https://fpm.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;fpm&lt;/a&gt;, and distribute it using your own packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can configure Choria to not install any gem dependencies via &lt;em&gt;Hiera&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective_choria::manage_gem_dependencies: false
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can then configure Choria to install these for you via the system packager, lets say you called the package &lt;em&gt;aio-nats-pure&lt;/em&gt;, again via &lt;em&gt;Hiera&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective_choria::package_dependencies:
  &amp;quot;aio-nats-pure&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;0.1.2&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will now install this package for you and allow you to manage the version of it, ordering is handled correctly and MCollective will restart appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Orchestrator</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/app_orchestration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/configuration/app_orchestration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Choria includes an Open Source Orchestrator compatible with the Puppet Site catalog system that allows you to describe a multi node deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This orchestrator interprets the environment graphs Puppet produces and runs your nodes in the right order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It uses the standard Puppet agent, best installed with ripienaar/mcollective_agent_puppet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use it requires some careful configuration, see the bottom of this page for details of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Puppet Site catalogs allow you describe a graph of multiple nodes, their dependencies, ordering and exchange information between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a sample site with a Lamp stack:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-puppet&#34;&gt;site {
  lamp{&#39;app2&#39;:
    db_user       =&amp;gt; &#39;user&#39;,
    db_password   =&amp;gt; &#39;secret&#39;,
    web_instances =&amp;gt; 3,
    nodes         =&amp;gt; {
      Node[&#39;dev1.example.net&#39;] =&amp;gt; Lamp::Mysql[&#39;app2&#39;],
      Node[&#39;dev2.example.net&#39;] =&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[&#39;app2-1&#39;],
      Node[&#39;dev3.example.net&#39;] =&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[&#39;app2-2&#39;],
      Node[&#39;dev4.example.net&#39;] =&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[&#39;app2-3&#39;]
    }
  }

  lamp{&#39;app1&#39;:
    db_user       =&amp;gt; &#39;user&#39;,
    db_password   =&amp;gt; &#39;secret&#39;,
    web_instances =&amp;gt; 3,
    nodes         =&amp;gt; {
      Node[&#39;dev1.example.net&#39;] =&amp;gt; Lamp::Mysql[&#39;app1&#39;],
      Node[&#39;dev2.example.net&#39;] =&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[&#39;app1-1&#39;],
      Node[&#39;dev3.example.net&#39;] =&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[&#39;app1-2&#39;],
      Node[&#39;dev4.example.net&#39;] =&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[&#39;app1-3&#39;]
    }
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can infer from this that there are node groups and that the &lt;em&gt;Lamp::Mysql&lt;/em&gt; needs to be done prior to any &lt;em&gt;Lamp::Webapp&lt;/em&gt;.  The orchastration part of this involves running Puppet in the desired order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool will ask Puppet for the catalog, and after analysing it for cyclic dependencies, view or deploy it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ mco choria run
Puppet Site Plan for the production Environment

2 applications on 4 managed nodes:

        Lamp[app1]
        Lamp[app2]

Node groups and run order:
   ------------------------------------------------------------------
        dev1.example.net
                Lamp[app1] -&amp;gt; Lamp::Mysql[app1]
                Lamp[app2] -&amp;gt; Lamp::Mysql[app2]

   ------------------------------------------------------------------
        dev2.example.net
                Lamp[app1] -&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[app1-1]
                Lamp[app2] -&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[app2-1]

        dev3.example.net
                Lamp[app1] -&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[app1-2]
                Lamp[app2] -&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[app2-2]

        dev4.example.net
                Lamp[app1] -&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[app1-3]
                Lamp[app2] -&amp;gt; Lamp::Webapp[app2-3]

Are you sure you wish to run this plan? (y/n) y

        2016-07-14 13:28:38 +0200: Checking if 4 nodes are enabled
        2016-07-14 13:28:38 +0200: Disabling Puppet on 4 nodes: Disabled during orchastration job initiated by rip.mcollective at 2016-07-14 13:28:38 +0200

Running node group 1 with 1 nodes batched 4 a time
        2016-07-14 13:28:38 +0200: Waiting for 1 nodes to become idle
        2016-07-14 13:28:38 +0200: Enabling Puppet on 1 nodes
        2016-07-14 13:28:38 +0200: Running Puppet on 1 nodes
        2016-07-14 13:28:38 +0200: Waiting for 1 nodes to start a run
        2016-07-14 13:28:43 +0200: Waiting for 1 nodes to become idle
        2016-07-14 13:29:03 +0200: Waiting for 1 nodes to become idle
        2016-07-14 13:29:24 +0200: Waiting for 1 nodes to become idle

Succesful run of 1 nodes in group 1 in 61.46 seconds

Running node group 2 with 3 nodes batched 4 a time
        2016-07-14 13:29:39 +0200: Waiting for 3 nodes to become idle
        2016-07-14 13:29:39 +0200: Enabling Puppet on 3 nodes
        2016-07-14 13:29:39 +0200: Running Puppet on 3 nodes
        2016-07-14 13:29:39 +0200: Waiting for 3 nodes to start a run
        2016-07-14 13:29:45 +0200: Waiting for 3 nodes to become idle
        2016-07-14 13:30:05 +0200: Waiting for 3 nodes to become idle
        2016-07-14 13:30:26 +0200: Waiting for 3 nodes to become idle

Succesful run of 3 nodes in group 2 in 61.78 seconds

        2016-07-14 13:30:41 +0200: Enabling Puppet on 4 nodes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuration&#34;&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up involves a few things, the instructions below work with the FOSS stack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should already have security certificates setup for Choria, run _mco choria request&lt;em&gt;cert&lt;/em&gt; if not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your Puppet Server is found by looking in DNS or manual config as per the deployment guide, defaults to &lt;em&gt;puppet:8140&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On your PuppetServer use the _puppetlabs/puppet&lt;em&gt;authorization&lt;/em&gt; module to add a authorization rule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-puppet&#34;&gt;puppet_authorization::rule { &amp;quot;puppetlabs environment&amp;quot;:
  match_request_path   =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;/puppet/v3/environment&amp;quot;,
  match_request_type   =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;path&amp;quot;,
  match_request_method =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;get&amp;quot;,
  allow                =&amp;gt; [&amp;quot;*.mcollective&amp;quot;],
  sort_order           =&amp;gt; 510,
  path                 =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;/etc/puppetlabs/puppetserver/conf.d/auth.conf&amp;quot;,
  notify               =&amp;gt; Class[&amp;quot;puppetserver::config&amp;quot;]
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives certificates *.mcollective access to the environment graph, adjust to local taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add in the old /etc/puppetlabs/puppet/auth.conf add an entry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;path /puppet/v3/environment
method find
allow *
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your &lt;em&gt;/etc/puppetlabs/puppet/puppet.conf&lt;/em&gt; add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ini&#34;&gt;[master]
app_management = true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally you need to have authorization to use the actions needed on the Puppet Agent, you can give yourself these by adding the following data to Hiera if you do not already have AAA rules, in this manner you can allow app runs to just certain environments, machines or whichever nodes you like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;mcollective_agent_puppet::policies:
  - action: &amp;quot;allow&amp;quot;
    callers: &amp;quot;puppet=rip.mcollective&amp;quot;
    actions: &amp;quot;disable,enable,last_run_summary,runonce,status&amp;quot;
    facts: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
    classes: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;logic-flow&#34;&gt;Logic Flow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea for what these deployments actually do, this is the logic flow they take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it has the site catalog from the Puppet Server it finds the list of all nodes in the site and also groups of them and the order to run in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checks if all the nodes are enabled, if any are disabled it cannot continue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disables all the nodes so no automated or human triggered runs can interfere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waits for all nodes to become idle, if after a long timeout they don&amp;rsquo;t exit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iterate the groups finding the nodes per group, loop them possibly in small batches

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable Puppet on these nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Puppet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait for it to start, exit if they do not idle after a long time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait for it to become idle, exit if they do not go idle after a long time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable them all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If any of the nodes had failed resources, fail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable all the nodes on success, Disable all the nodes on fail since the stack is now inconsistent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is some improvements to be made, specifically there&amp;rsquo;s a small window between
running the nodes and disabling them again that another run can start, end of the
day though it works out, all the daemons are idle when the status is fetched and
this is definitely for a run started after the one we needed.  So the end out come
is the same&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Status&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic feature work and it works with the Open Source PuppetServer too, but the feature in Puppet is extremely new and needs some improvement, this tool is going to be only as good as what Puppet provides.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference</title>
      <link>http://docs.choria.io/reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.choria.io/reference/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section provide reference information about the plugins included in Choria.  You do not need to read or understand these to use Choria but they provide more in depth information if you are curious or want to see what is customizable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>